MICHAEL ROSENGART: Thrusters.
Right now, we're going to get into a more complicated exercise.
We're integrating more of the body.
And we're going to develop more strength because we're getting more of the body parts working together at the same time in cohesion.
Okay.
So, Jonesy, you want to go ahead and show what a thruster is?
Jonesy going to take a couple of dumbbells, bring it up to his shoulders.
And we're, basically, he's going to sit back into a squat.
And we're basically combining a squat and a shoulder press, but it's not that simple.
It's not segmented like that.
Jonesy is going to sit back.
And as he drives up, again, driving on his heel, driving his hips forward is the work from his hips that will then force the arms up.
Good.
And then there's a lot of arm strength involved to stabilize the dumbbell right above his shoulders.
Not out to the side, not back, but right above.
That's good.
Good work, Jonesy.
Again working from the heels up, work with your breath; feel that you're driving your hips forward and up each time, good work.
Do ten of those and we're going to take a three to five minute break, and then come back to it.
Again, I want to make sure that you understand that when you're doing the thruster that it's working from the ground up, and it is one smooth movement.
It's not segmented.
It's not the squat and a shoulder press, okay?
It's one smooth movement.
Try it.